Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
A half-century has passed since humanity began moving...
...its burgeoning population into space.
These gigantic space colonies orbiting the Earth...
...became a second home to humanity...
...where people were born and raised...
...and where they died.
It is the year 0079 of the Universal Century.
The cluster of colonies furthest from Earth, known as Side 3...
...proclaimed themselves the Principality of Zeon.
And launched a war of independence against the Earth Federation.
In roughly one month of fighting, the Principality of Zeon...
...and the Federation Forces caused the deaths of half the total population.
Humanity was horrified by its own actions.
Destroy Gundam!
I don't care if they're civilians!
Just get me some help!
Oh no! Look out!
Where's my Yuri?!
Come back!
Get on board the White Base!
Yuri!
Hang on tight!
Hurry!
Fraw Bow! Get to the White Base! Hurry!
A mobile suit!
Amuro? Are you in that mobile suit?
Go! Soon, there'll be no air left here!
Okay!
Captain! I'll take over!
Please return to the ship!
You're only a pilot cadet.
Can you fire this thing?
I can certainly try!
I'll leave it to you, then!
Captain!
A-Are you all right?
Yes, sir!
You followed my orders, as well as Denim's.
You have nothing to worry about, Slender.
Thank you, sir!
But it's hard to believe...
...the Federation mobile suit has
the kind of performance you describe.
Yes, I understand, sir. But I saw it myself.
Ensign.
Yes, sir?
Open a laser communication channel.
Contact Vice Admiral Dozle.
Yes, sir!
You'll be safe here on the ship. Just sit still.
You, down there!
You can tie bandages, right?
Could you help us out?
Sure!
I promise to go look for
your mothers later, okay?
Over there.
Right.
Excuse me...
Oh, yes. We need your help over here.
Please clean that wound and
get some suture tape on it.
Right.
Are you sure the Zeon ship has ceased fire?
Yes, sir!
Good. You have my permission to return.
Captain! You're here!
Captain.
The Zeon attack has wiped out
virtually all defense personnel.
How are things on your end?
Every soldier and engineer at
Side 7 has been killed.
All because of just two Zakus.
Of the injured soldiers,
less than 10 are combat-ready.
Get all the Gundam components
on board at once.
Yes, sir.
Fortunately, we have one man
piloting a Gundam.
He is transferring a Guncannon
and Guntank on board now.
Who's the pilot?
We haven't confirmed his identity yet.
Once he's finished, get the White Base
away from Side 7 at once.
Yes, sir. But the pilot of the White Base...
The computer can take us out.
But sir...
Excuse me.
I'm licensed to operate cruiser-class
space gliders, if that helps any.
And you are?
Mirai Yashima, sir.
Oh, I see. Of the famous Yashima family.
We were all set to celebrate the successful
completion of your mission last night...
But since you dawdled and didn't show up,
our banquet preparations were all for nothing!
We've discovered the Federation's
Operation V, Admiral Dozle.
What? Operation V?
Yes, sir. They've developed mobile suits.
We've also identified a brand-new
Federation battleship.
Char, the Red Comet, strikes again.
So, what else?
We were on our way back home...
...so we've used up all our
missiles and ammunition.
You need supplies, huh? You'll have them!
Thank you, sir.
We also need three more Zakus.
You lost three Zaku mobile suits?!
Yes, Vice Admiral. Two were lost to
a single Federation mobile suit.
All right. You'll get your Zakus.
I want all the data you can get
on Operation V.
And capture that mobile suit If possible.
I will try, sir.
Good.
Ensign! Get me three commandos.
But sir, aren't we going to wait
for the supply ship?
In war, you must think two or three moves
ahead of the enemy.
Slender escaped from there.
Logically, we can do just the opposite, right?
What? Who's piloting it?
Somebody called Amuro.
Never heard of him.
Perhaps he was one of the pilots
testing it at Side 7, sir.
You can contact the Gundam
using the panel on the left.
Yes, sir.
Have the Gundam cover the White Base
when it leaves port.
Where's the channel control?
Should be there, on the right console.
Ms. Mirai, how goes it?
I understand the basic operations.
But the engine control...
Ryu can search for trained personnel...
...if anyone comes back here...
You're Amuro?
Is that really the Gundam's cockpit?
What's wrong?
It's a child!
Some kid is piloting the Gundam!
What?!
That's Amuro?!
Take a look for yourself.
This boy is in the Gundam.
And he's no pilot.
How can this be?
How can a child pilot the Gundam?!
That boy...!
You know him?
I don't know him well, but at Side 7
he's well-known for his love of machines.
Is that boy the one who
took down Zeon's Zakus?
I was only able to beat them
thanks to the Gundam's abilities.
What are you doing there?
That voice...!
You must be the person who ordered
me to load the Gundam components.
I'll remove him, Captain.
Only If we have any surviving pilots...
You take the residential block.
Yes. Leave it to me!
Come on, Chief. You can make it.
Hey, what are you two doing here?
The Captain's ordered us to
look for anyone left behind.
Excuse me!
Are there any other people left?
Beats me. I was busy avoiding blasts
and barely made it here myself.
You guys coming?
H-Hey, you...!
And you call yourself a man? Coward!
What's your problem?
A coward like you ought to be
left here at Side 7.
Well, look at you on your high horse.
I know you. You're Say... Sayla, right?
Something like that?
Stop talking to me
like some kind of street punk!
Fraw Bow!
Right!
Hey you! Give us a hand.
All right.
Activate engines, 3 percent thrust.
Mega particle cannons, standby.
Target Side 7's space gate.
But avoid direct hits to the docking bay!
Good job, Ensign.
Slender.
Sir!
We can enter via this maintenance airlock.
All right, go!
Looks like another attack.
What do we do about Amuro, Captain?
Operator.
What's attacking us?
Sir!
The same Musai-class warship approaching
40 degrees port-stern.
Destroy any of the Gundam
components that we can't use.
Issue a beam rifle to the Gundam.
Huh?
He's a bit young to go into battle...
But historically, there have been
15-year-old soldiers before.
I'm counting on all of you.
Yes, Captain.
Amuro, do you hear me?
Destroy the Gundam components
left at Side 7.
Why? There're enough parts for three more...
We can't let Zeon find out our secrets!
Something's odd...
The Musai's falling back.
Falling back?
Amuro, do you know what to do?
I could use that "super napalm" thing.
Captain?
Amuro's judgment is correct.
Leave it to him.
The ship will launch soon!
Is there anyone left here?
I'm going to Amuro's!
Be back in time for dinner!
If there's anyone left, please respond!
Are there any survivors here?
Any survivors?
No survivors...
Mobile Suit
Don't move!
Drop it!
You're brave.
You don't look like a soldier or a guerrilla.
Move, and I'll shoot!
She looks like...
Please take off the helmet!
And face the other way!
But... she's too strong...
...to be Artesia.
That's... a Zeon soldier!
...My brother?
I'm going to use the super napalm!
Please climb onto my hand.
We're destroying all of the
mobile suit parts here.
Amuro. You're sure it was a Zeon soldier?
That's right.
Please lie down in the hand.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Mr. Bright! A Zeon soldier
just entered the space port!
What?!
Close all hatches on the White Base.
All of those who can hold a gun...
All hands! Fire on the Zeon soldier
approaching the bow! Move it!
All members of the recon team.
Escape at once.
Please launch immediately!
Damn!
Lt. Commander!
They're right behind me.
All right.
I'm going to fire. I'm going to fire.
I'm going to fire!
Lt. Commander!
Stay calm.
If you move, you're more likely to be hit.
Small targets like humans
aren't so easy to hit.
Musai! Do you read? It's me!
This Is the Musai. We have identified you,
Lt. Commander.
The enemy's moving out.
Use the laser line...
...and launch my Zaku and Slender's
with type 1 equipment.
Roger.
Prepare to launch Zakus! Heading RD23.5.
Gate sensor, 360 degrees,
all roger.
You're too tense.
Don't worry. The computer'll take care of it.
Yes, sir.
Hailing Amuro, in the Gundam.
You're too far from the White Base.
Stay within 10 km to starboard of the ship.
Roger.
Check that each block is airtight.
Can you do that?
Yes, sir!
Operators.
Our helmsman is a rookie.
Give her time to respond to directions.
We'll do what we have to do.
Thank you.
The engine output gauge is to the right.
I understand.
Keep it out of the red zone.
Yes, sir.
Missile stores are shown on the indicator...
I know. This one here, right?
You catch on quick.
All blocks! Prepare to intercept!
Leaving the docking bay.
Increase main engine power!
Hard to starboard!
Bright!
Core Fighter okay to launch!
Ryu, are you sure you can do this?
Of course. I'm a pilot cadet!
I suppose that's better than a complete
novice. Any flight experience?
Two simulations.
So he's basically the same as Amuro.
High-intensity heat sources approaching!
Missiles?
Large missiles!
Evasive maneuvers!
12 degrees to port, 8 degrees down!
Mirai!
Y-Yes, sir!
Too late!
I've got them! Let me shoot them!
Go to it!
I'm launching now!
These, I can handle.
Hit it!
Two more objects approaching the ship!
What are they?!
Looks like mobile suits, sir.
Zakus?!
B-But Mr. Bright, no Zaku
is capable of that speed!
One Zaku is approaching
at three times the normal speed!
It's Char!
The Red Comet...!
What was that? Captain?
Char, the Red Comet?!
At the Battle of Loum...
...Char single-handedly
destroyed five of our battleships.
Get us out of here!
Let's test the performance
of the Federation's mobile suit!
I'll take him!
A Zaku is not a human! Even I can...!
No, Amuro! You're not ready!
I can do it!
I'll stop you!
How's that?
Impossible! That was a direct hit!
S-So this is battle...!
It's... It's coming!
Fast! What maneuverability!
Are you there, Slender? Get behind him!
Lt. Commander! What is that?!
He has a new weapon?!
Who cares, as long as it doesn't hit us!
Cover me!
The Core Fighter will cover you!
But don't deplete the beam rifle's energy!
I don't need to be told that...
Behind you! Ascend!
The Core Fighter...
I've got you!
Slender!
One shot... Destroyed in one shot...!
How can this be?!
Is that mobile suit equipped with
a battleship-class beam cannon?!
A-A Zaku... w-with one shot...!
You won't get away with this!
Just a new type of fighter. Nothing special.
The beam rifle's energy...!
I... I used it all up!
I can't match that firepower!
The Gundam has returned to the ship.
Once the loading is finished,
have Ryu and Amuro report to the bridge.
Yes, sir!
Put the White Base on course for Luna II.
All personnel must remain at their stations
and alternate rest shifts.
Here they come.
Bright, status on the enemy?
They haven't moved. But, knowing Char...
...they will come after us.
Amuro!
You rely too much on
the Gundam's performance.
You need to be more efficient in battle.
What?!
Grow up!
Once you were assigned to the Gundam,
you became a pilot!
Your duty is to protect the ship.
What did you say?!
I hate to say it,
but that's the way things are.
If you can't handle it,
then go back to Side 7 now!
Mr. Bright!
I can't promise that I'm up to the task.
But... I don't have any other choice.
I think that you're a...
I don't mind if you hate me.
Go deal with the Gundam's maintenance!
Use whomever you need.
Amuro, you're responsible for it now.
Luna II...
An asteroid placed in
the moon's orbital path...
...to provide construction
materials for the space colonies.
This is now the location...
...of the Federation's front-line base.
As Char's Musai takes on supplies...
The Gundam and the Core Fighter take
this opportunity to launch an attack.
However, Zeon has soldiers
aside from Char.
The thunderous roar of the battle rages.
Mobile Suit Gundam.
Next episode... Vote to Attack.
Next Time
Vote to Attack!
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...